

Maciej Ostrowski

Senior Software Developer

Has 15 years of professional experience. Possess extensive knowledge and experience in various areas of software development, including a comprehensive understanding of Back-End Web and DevOps development. Looking for new opportunities in fields of Java, Cloud, Distributed Systems and Big Data.



mmm.ostrowski@gmail.com



(+48) 881-697-201



Poznań, Poland



linkedin.com/in/mmostrowski



github.com/mmmostrowski



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer Informatica Inc.

06/2022 - 12/2022 Remotely

Informatica is a leading big data management company in Silicon Valley, founded in 1993.

Achievements

- As a member of the CDI-E R&D team, assisted with Cloud Data Integration.
- Optimized connector sizes by a factor of 3 for multiple Hive distributions.
- Implemented several functional use cases and resolved various bugs within a Java and Scala-based code on a microservice architecture.
- Implemented a dedicated automation script in Bash for AWS clusters.
- Elevated the user experience by refining the ANTLR grammar of Parameter Files.
- Improved the automation of local development process, resulting in reduced manual efforts and faster development cycle.
- Technology Stack: Java, Scala, Bash, Apache Spark, Apache Hive, AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, ANTLR, Maven, Spring Boot, JUnit, Mockito, Microservices, Perforce.

Senior DevOps Engineer Creatuity Corp.

01/2019 - 05/2022 Remotely

Creatuity is a leading developer of innovative Magento e-commerce solutions worldwide.

Achievements

- Developed highly-automated, multi-project Continuous Integration platform used effectively to establish development processes for about 100 of varied Magento 2 stores.
- Platform Provides 'one command' access to the development of any of active Magento projects. Supports local development on Linux, Windows and Mac workstations.
- System automatically fetches changes being made by users and customers on production store like product changes or new orders. All developers have 'one command' access to those changes.
- Platform provides stability, flexibility, good performance and components reusability. It is being developed for all active projects at the same time.
- Technology stack: Bash, Docker, Magento 2, Atlassian Stack, Automate testing.



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Experience

Web, DevOps, Desktop, Software Architecture, E-commerce, Big Data

Main Programming Languages

PHP (10 years), Bash (5 years), Java (4 vears)

Other Programming Languages used professionally

JavaScript / HTML / CSS (5 years), C++ (2 years), C# (half a year), Scala (half a year)

Software Engineering

strong OOP, performance optimizations, architecture & code design, S.O.L.I.D. in practice, experience with multi-threading programming

Algorithmics

solid book knowledge, practice with algorithmic competitions

DevOps

strong Bash and Docker skills

OS

Linux, Windows



BeSharp Framework (04/2021 - Present) 🗹

- research & development project
- enhances procedural Bash language by an OOP paradigm

⊗ WORK EXPERIENCE

Director of Technology Creatuity Corp.

06/2016 - 01/2019

Poznań, Poland & Dallas TX, USA

Achievements

- Was coordinating three IT managers and supervise about 20 technicians and other professionals to provide guidance.
- Established a common development environment and practices for three offices in Poland and Texas, US.
- Was responsible for recruitment process for technical positions. Has completed approximately a hundred of job interviews for programmer positions.
- Established an education and promotion standards on technical positions.

Magento Senior Developer

Creatuity Corp.

09/2012 - 06/2016

Poznań, Poland & Dallas TX, USA

Achievements

- Worked on the development of new Magento stores. Actively maintained the existing Magento stores.
- Was a Technical Leader of demanding Magento projects.
- Was a member of a closed conference for Magento Team Leaders from the Europe. The Magento Team was collecting feedback on the upcoming version 2 of the Magento platform.
- Developed one of the most challenging Magento Catalog integrations in Europe.
- Received the award in person from the head of the eBay Enterprise.
- Technology stack: Magento 2, PHP, Ubuntu Linux.

Web Developer

Korbanek Sp. z o.o.

06/2015 - 02/2019

Poznań, Poland

Korbanek is the biggest agricultural machinery supplier in Poland. Achievements

- Developed a CMS website containing more than 5 000 pages.
- Managed back-end development, executed the site migration process, and handled technical project management responsibilities.
- Technology stack: PHP, Drupal, Continuous Delivery, Linux.

Java Programmer UNIDOC

08/2012 - 05/2013

Remotely

Unidoc is a mature and advanced business platform with Document Management System features.

Achievements

- Implemented a dedicated load balancing software for OCR processing servers.
- Enhanced Apache PDFBox desktop Java application by OCR related features.
- Technology stack: Java Spring, Java Swing, Multi Threading, Linux.

PHP Programmer

Tablica.pl / Allegro Group

08/2011 - 06/2012 Poznań, Poland

Tablica.pl (today known as OLX) was then the 3rd most visited website in the Poland.

Achievements

- Designed and implemented a remake of Business Intelligence application.
- Application fixed data reporting stability and has significantly increased flexibility.
- Was actively maintaining the most popular classifieds portals from a couple of countries in Africa, Asia and Europe.



Magento 2 Extension Challenge (03/2015 - 04/2015)

Magento 2 Team, E-Bay Enterprise

- 3-rd place winner of international competition
- designed and implemented a framework to develop extensions compatible with both, Magento and Magento 2 platforms at once



English

Professional Working Proficiency

Polish Native



Software Development

- Toject Managemen

Problem Solving

Research

Adaptability

Analytical



CERTIFICATES

Magento Certified Developer Plus (01/2015 - 12/2022)



EDUCATION

Software Engineering

Adam Mickiewicz University Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science

2004 - 2009

Poznań, Poland

Note

dropped at 5-th year



INTERESTS

Mathematics

Music



C++ Developer

Rockwool

02/2008 - 07/2010

Cigacice, Poland

Rockwool Group is a Danish multinational manufacturer of mineral wool products.

Achievements

- Developed a dedicated desktop application for collaborative truck spedition and reporting.
- Application was successfully coordinating trucks for two company branches.
- Technology stack: C++, MFC, MySQL, SMS Gateway.

Full Stack Programmer

Freelance

05/2007 - 08/2011

Achievements

- Provided various kind of Desktop and Web programming services.
- Programming languages: Java, PHP, C++, C#, JavaScript.
- Technology Stack: Java Spring, GWT, C++ STL, custom PHP framework, Drupal, .Net, MFC, WPF, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, OpenGL 3D, Windows OS.

Junior PHP Programmer / Network AdministratorKEIPER

09/2006 - 05/2007

Świebodzin, Poland

The Keiper GmbH & Co. KG was a German automotive supplier.

Achievements

- Developed a dedicated support ticketing system in a custom php framework.
- Helped IT team with maintenance of hundred of workstations.
- Technology Stack: PHP, Novell NetWare.

REFERENCES

Joshua Warren CEO

"(...) Maciej at all times was extremely competent, specific and oriented on quality, at the same time very friendly and helpful. His analytical skills and approach were helpful at every level of planning and his solid knowledge on programming helped Creatuity to grow many senior developers. (...)"

josh@creatuity.com - +1214-810-5005